

SIRAJ UL ISLAM

Python Developer

2+ years of experience with the ability to solve problems, be able to quickly grep complex systems, and identify opportunities for improvement and resolution of critical issues. I am keen to learn and implement new things to improve processes and quality. Python knowledge, web development in Python Django, Rest Framework, QA methodologies & processes, and working experience with Selenium Web-Driver, MySQL, and SQLite are all assets. I would like to work in a competitive environment where I can utilize my analytical, interpersonal, and organizational skills. To conceive and achieve solutions that will help the organization in meeting its targets, thereby enhancing my own skills as an individual and a team player.

\times

sirajulislam.khilji@gmail.com



+923359723496



HQ 4, Shami Road Younis Line, Lahore, PAKISTAN



linkedin.com/in/siraj-ul-islam

SKILLS

SQL

Python / PHP

MI Data Science

Diango web Framework

Rest Framework

OOP

Data Structure and Algorithm Analysis

Statistic/ Probability/ Mathematics

HTML / CSS / Bootstrap/

Requirement Engineering

Web Scraping and Crawling

Selenium Automation and Manual Testing

Problem Solving

Deployments

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Urdu

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Pashto

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

EDUCATION

Software Engineering

Institute of Management Science Khyber Pakhtunkhwa

08/2017 - 07/202

Peshawar , Pakistan , CGPA 3.26

Diploma Information TechnologyKhyber Pakhtunkhwa Board of Technical Education

05/2016 - 05/2017

Peshawar, Pakistan, Marks 86%

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Python Developer (02/2022 - Present)

Working as a Python Django and Python core developer, I'm developing a business web system front-end, back-end, and deployments of the system on a Centos server. **Projects**: Creation and Optimization of Dashboards and Business Websites. **Location**: **Aitomation Pyt Ltd, Phase 6 DHA, Lahore**

Associate Python Django and SQA Automation Engineer

I have two responsibilities. 1. As a Python Django developer, I create and deploy a business web system. 2. SOA Engineer-Manual and Automated Testing, creates and manages technical documents like test plans, test cases, bug reporting, test reports, etc. Web Automation Testing with Selenium (web driver) using the Python Language, TestNG/JUnit, pytest, etc. **Projects** include converting old traffic code to new traffic for business process automation; creating and testing dashboards and business websites; automating Facebook Pages; and scraping data from various websites. **Location**: **Aitomation Pvt Ltd, Phase 6 DHA, Lahore**

Software Developer(Python Django) (12/2021 - 01/2022)

When the company promoted me than I start working on the Web App Dashboard Bussiness Application most of the time. I worked here on the back-end as well as the front-end. **Projects**: Shopping Carts System, Gaming Management System, Bussiness Dashboards. **Location**: **National Center Of Artificial Intelligence UET Peshawar**

Junior Software Engineer

Here my responsibility is to create a data set for the AI Application, train the model and create the front end using Python Django. **Project**: surveillance and Object Detection Models Through Deep Learning, Web Apps local management systems. **Location**: **National Center Of Artificial Intelligence UET Peshawar**

Software Engineer (Internship) (08/2021 - 11/2021)

This is my first company where I started my career as a software engineer. During my first time, I worked on python Django on the front end. When I completed 2 months, I started working on the back-end and, as a python SQA Automation, **Projects:** Tailor Automation System, Web Base Database and Sports Website, Wedding Halls Online Automation System. **Location**: **WAK-IT Solution Deans Plaza Peshawar**

CERTIFICATES

Machine Learning A- Z^{TM} : Hands-On Python In Data Science , Data Warehousing for Business Intelligence Specialization, Complete Python (2021)

Udemy , Coursera

Python For Everyone, Advanced Python Django with react Course, (2022)

Coursea, Udemy

Python Django with Rest Framework react Front-End (2022)

Coursea, Udemy

SQL, Tableau, Power BI, Python, Machine Learning in Python, Deep Learning, Data Science, Statistics, Probability, Mathematics (2021)

Data Scientist Courses From 365datascience

ACHIEVEMENTS

Amazon Web Services - Solutions Architect (Associate), AWS Data Analytics

Advanced Digital Skills and Global Certifications program under KPYEP conducted by The Gen Web Services (Genese)